Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations WEB.ARC.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Union of Clerical, Administrative & Technical Staff, NYU Local 3882, NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO (UCATS) Archived Website, Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing; American Federation of Teachers. Local 3882 (Clerical Union).
  Union of Clerical, Administrative & Technical Staff, Local 3882,, NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO (UCATS), founded in 1978, is a labor union that represents over 1500 clerical, administrative, and technical staff at New York University. They are affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers and were formerly known as the United Staff Association of NYU. The website contains the current contract, their newsletter, Momentum, and their blog.
  New York University.; Clerks |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York |x History |y 20th century.; Universities and colleges |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Union Songs Archived Website, Aug 10, 2009 - ongoing; Union Songs.
  Union Songs is an online collection of lyrics, discography, bibliography, and filmography of songs related to the labor movement. The website contains links to union music and other cultural sites. The coverage is international, but the coverage of Australia is extensive. The website contains over 770 songs and poems and over 300 authors.
  Working class--Songs and music.
- UnionBook Archived Website, Feb 9, 2011 - ongoing; UnionBook.
  UnionBook is a social networking website for trade unionists and a project of LabourStart. The website has a microblogging feature called the Wire.
  Labor movement.; Labor union members.; Labor unions |x Officials and employees.; Online social networks.
- Unions.org Archived Website, Mar 3, 2013 - ongoing; Unions.org
  Unions.org is an online union directory that lists unions by name, state, and city. The entries are fully searchable and include addresses, management names, phone numbers, and office map descriptions. The website contains over 15,000 local union listings.
- UNITE HERE (Organization) Archived Website, Mar 24, 2009 - ongoing; UNITE HERE (Organization)
  UNITE HERE is the merger of two labor unions, the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE) and the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union (HERE). UNITE HERE, founded in 2004, is a labor union in the United States and Canada with more than 265,000 active members. The union's members work predominantly in the hotel, food service, laundry, warehouse, and casino gaming industries. It is currently affiliated with the AFL-CIO.
  Clothing workers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Service industries workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- United American Nurses (UAN) Archived Website, Dec 8, 2009 - Sep 7, 2011; United American Nurses, AFL-CIO
  United American Nurses (UAN) was an American union affiliated with the AFL-CIO. Founded in 1999 and dissolved in 2009, it represented registered nurses (RNs). In 2009, UAN merged with the California Nurses Association/National Nurses Organizing Committee and Massachusetts Nurses Association to form National Nurses United.
- United Association for Labor Education Archived Website, Aug 10, 2009 - ongoing; United Association for Labor Education.
  The United Association for Labor Education (UALE), created out of a merger between the Workers’ Education Local 189 and the University and College Labor Education Association in 2000, is an international association for post-secondary, community, union and associated labor educators. The UALE co-publishes the Labor Studies Journal with West Virginia University.
  College teachers' unions |z United States.; Working class |x Education |z United States
- United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United States and Canada (UA) Archived Website, Jan 8, 2010 - ongoing; United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry.
  Founded in 1889, the United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing, Pipefitting and Sprinkler Fitting Industry of the United States and Canada, (United Association, UA) is a trade union of journeymen and apprentices of the plumbing, pipefitting, and sprinkler fitting industry of the United States and Canada. The members fabricate, install, and service piping systems. There are approximately 340,000 highly-skilled United Association members who belong to over 300 individual local unions across North America.
  Plumbers |x Labor unions |z North America.
- United Brotherhood Of Carpenters Archived Website, Apr 29, 2012 - ongoing; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.
  United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America (UBC), founded in 1881, is a building trade union with approximately a half-million members in the construction and wood-products industries. UBC members consist of carpenters, millwrights, interior systems and framing and residential carpenters, floor coverers, pile drivers, lathers, and millworkers and cabinetmakers. The website contains information on training programs, partnership programs, and legislative issues.
  Carpenters
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America: Cabinetmakers Local 2090 Archived Website, Feb 4, 2012 - ongoing; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 2090 (New York, N.Y.)
  The United Brotherhood of Carpenters Shop and Industrial Local 2790 was formed in August 2011, from the dissolution of the Architectural Woodworkers Local 2090 and Industrial Local 2870. UBC Local Union 2790 is a specialty trade union that represents carpenters, industrial shop workers, architectural woodworkers, millworkers, finish carpenters, wood finishers, cabinet installers, trim carpenters, architectural metal workers, and cabinetmakers throughout the five boroughs of New York City; as well as Long Island, New Jersey, and Westchester County. Local 2790 is part of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters & Joiners of America, and the New York City District Council of Carpenters. The website includes news listings, wages and benefits, event listings, images, and other reports.
  Cabinetmakers |z United States.; Carpenters |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (UE) Archived Website, May 13, 2012 - ongoing; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America.
  United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America or the Rank-and-File Union (UE) is a national union representing some 35,000 workers in a wide variety of manufacturing, public sector and private non-profit sector jobs. UE is an independent union (not affiliated with the AFL-CIO). Members work in electrical manufacturing, metalworking and plastics as plastic injection molders, tool and die makers, sheet metal workers, truck drivers, warehouse workers, and custodians. The website contains a blog, information for workers and unions, and political action campaigns.
  Electric industry workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- United Farm Workers of America (UFW) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; United Farm Workers of America.
  Founded in 1962 by Cesar Chavez, the United Farm Workers of America represents farm workers in the United States. Formed from the merger of the Agricultural Workers Organizing Committee and the National Farm Workers Association, it is affiliated with the Change to Win Federation.
  Agricultural laborers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- United Federation of Teachers Archived Website, Sep 26, 2007 - ongoing; United Federation of Teachers.
  The United Federation of Teachers (Local 2 of the American Federation of Teachers) represents more than 200,000 people, and is the sole bargaining agent for most of the non-supervisory educators who work in the New York City public schools. It represents approximately 74,000 teachers and 17,000 classroom paraprofessionals, along with school secretaries, attendance teachers, guidance counselors, psychologists, social workers, education evaluators, nurses, laboratory technicians, adult education teachers and 32,000 retired members. The UFT also represents teachers and other employees of some private educational institutions. The allied Federation of Nurses/UFT represents some 2,500 registered nurses of the New York City Visiting Nurse Service and several private New York City hospitals and health care institutions. The union led a successful organizing drive to gain collective-bargaining rights for 28,000 New York City home child-care providers in 2007. The website includes bargaining agreements, their blog, EdWize, benefits, event and news listings, and their platform.
  Education |z New York (State) |z New York.; Teachers' unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- United Food and Commercial Workers International Union (UFCW) Archived Website, Dec 3, 2009 - ongoing; United Food and Commercial Workers International Union.
  The United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, founded in 1979, is a labor union representing approximately 1.3 million workers in the United States and Canada in many industries, including agriculture, health care, meatpacking, poultry and food processing, manufacturing, textile, chemical trades, and retail food. It is affiliated with the Change to Win Coalition.
  Food Industry and Trade |x Employees |x Labor Unions; Food industry and trade |x Employees|x Labor unions |z Canada.
- United Mine Workers of America (UMWA) Archived Website, Dec 9, 2009 - ongoing; United Mine Workers of America.
  Founded in 1890, The United Mine Workers of America is a North American labor union which has represented coal miners and coal technicians. Today, the Union also represents health care workers, truck drivers, manufacturing workers and public employees in the United States and Canada.
  Coal miners |x Labor unions |z United States.
- United Steel, Paper and Forestry, Rubber, Manufacturing, Energy, Allied Industrial & Service Workers International Union (USW) Archived Website, Sep 15, 2011 - ongoing; United Steel, Paper and Forestry, Rubber, Manufacturing, Energy, Allied Industrial & Service Workers International Union
  The United Steel, Paper and Forestry, Rubber, Manufacturing, Energy, Allied Industrial and Service Workers International Union (United Steelworkers or USW), founded in 1942, is the largest industrial labor union in North America, with 705,000 members. Headquartered in Pittsburgh, U.S., the United Steelworkers represents workers in the United States, Canada and the Caribbean. The United Steelworkers represent workers in a diverse range of industries, including primary and fabricated metals, chemicals, glass, rubber, heavy-duty conveyor belting, tires, transportation, utilities, container industries, pharmaceuticals, call centers and health care.
  Iron and steel workers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Steel industry and trade |z United States.
- United Transportation Union (UTU) Archived Website, Dec 9, 2009 - ongoing; United Transportation Union
  The United Transportation Union (UTU), founded in 1969, is a transportation labor union representing about 125,000 active and retired railroad, bus, mass transit, and airline workers in the United States with more than 600 locals. It is headquartered in Cleveland, OH and affiliated with the AFL-CIO.
- United Union of Roofers, Waterproofers and Allied Workers Archived Website, Dec 8, 2009 - ongoing; United Union of Roofers, Waterproofers and Allied Workers (Roofers and Waterproofers)
  The United Union of Roofers, Waterproofers and Allied Workers, founded in 1903, has approximately 22,000 members organized into nine district councils across the United States. Members participate in the National Roofing Industry Supplemental Pension, Multi-trade Organizing Volunteer Education program (MOVE), health and safety programs, as well as training and apprenticeship opportunities, and cooperative labor-management research and education efforts.
- United Workers Archived Website, May 13, 2011 - ongoing; United Workers
  The United Workers, founded in 2002 by homeless day laborers in Baltimore, is a human rights organization led by low-wage workers. They fight for fair development, which respects human rights, maximizes public benefits, and is sustainable. The organization focuses on understanding the root causes of poverty and organizing around universal human rights. They work for change through conferences and campaigns, including The Living Wages at Camden Yards Campaign.
  Day laborers |z Maryland |z Baltimore.; Homeless persons |z Maryland |z Baltimore.
- UPPNET Archived Website, Aug 9, 2009 - Jan 18, 2013; Union Producers and Programmers Network Online.
  The Union Producers and Programmers Network Online (UPPNET) provided links to television and radio programs for organized labor and working people, campaigned to make labor media a priority within the labor movement, and published the online UPPNET Newsletter. The site has been inactive since 2007.
  Labor radio stations.; Labor unions and mass media.; Radio producers and directors--Societies, etc.
- US Federation of Worker Cooperatives Archived Website, Nov 5, 2011 - ongoing; The United States Federation of Worker Cooperatives
  The United States Federation of Worker Cooperatives, founded in 2004, is a national grassroots membership organization of and for worker cooperatives, democratic workplaces, and organizations that support the growth and development of worker cooperatives. The organization offers resources and education for worker cooperatives.
  Producer cooperatives |z United States.
- US Labor Against the War Archived Website, Feb 12, 2013 - ongoing; U.S. Labor Against the War.
  U.S. Labor Against the War, was founded in 2003 in opposition to the Iraq War, Its principles include: to advocate, educate and mobilize in the US labor movement for: a just foreign policy that will bring genuine security and prosperity to working people and an end to U.S. occupation of foreign countries, replaced by the reconstruction of war-devastated nations with the full support of the international community and the full participation and decision-making power of affected peoples. The organization also supports the broader social justice ideals associated with the labor movement.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Protest movements |z United States.; Labor movement |x Political activity |z United States.
- Utility Workers of America, Local 1-2 Archived Website, Feb 19, 2009 - ongoing; Utility Workers Union of America. Local 1-2.
  Local 1-2 of the Utility Workers Union of America evolved out of the Utility Workers Organizing Committee (UWOC) established by the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) in 1938. In 1946, with more than 180 locals organized nationwide, the UWOC transformed itself into the Utility Workers Union of America, CIO. Local 1-2 represents New York area with members working in the electric, gas, water, and nuclear industries across the United States. The website includes information on their political action committee, their publication, the Record, images and other audiovisual materials, news listings, and event listings.
  Electric industry workers|x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Utility Workers Union of America (UWUA) Archived Website, Dec 9, 2009 - ongoing; Utility Workers Union of America (UWUA)
  The Utility Workers Union of America, AFL-CIO (UWUA), is a union with over 50,000 members working in the electric, gas, water, and nuclear industries across the United States. It represents utility workers in municipal, as well as publicly traded utilities. Fields include power generation (power plants), power distribution (transmission and distribution), call/service center employees, as well as natural gas and water utilities.
- Vermont Workers' Center Archived Website, May 15, 2011 - ongoing; Workers' Center
  IVermont Workers’ Center was founded in 1996 by a group of low-income workers in Central Vermont. The Vermont Workers' Center is a democratic, member-run organization dedicated to organizing for workers' rights and living wages for all Vermonters. They organize rallies, public hearings, forums, publicizing peoples' stories, and taking direct action, we support workers throughout the state who are trying to improve their wages, benefits, rights on the job, working conditions and their communities. It is affiliated with Jobs for Justice and Grassroots Global Justice.
  Labor movement |z Vermont.
- Whole Foods Market Workers Unite! Archived Website, Nov 15, 2014-ongoing; Whole Foods Workers Unite!.
  Whole Food Workers Unite is the organizing committee to organize a union for the employees of Whole Foods Market, a national supermarket chain in the United States. The workers are fighting for higher wages, consistent scheduling, paid time off, retirement plans, the ability to work full-time for new hires, safety, and an affordable health care plan. They are affiliated with the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW).The website contains a petition and a news wire.
  Whole Foods Market.; Service industries workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Wobbly City: Newsletter of the NYC Branch (IWW) Archived Website, Jul 27, 2009 - Oct 27, 2013; Industrial Workers of the World. NYC Branch.
  Wobbly City is the official blog of the New York City General Membership Branch (GMB) of the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW).
  Syndicalism--New York (N.Y.)
- Women on the Job Archived Website, Mar 9, 2009 - Dec 24, 2012; Women on the Job.
  Women on the Job (WOJ) was founded in 1981 as a private, not-for-profit advocacy organization dedicated to achieving women’s equality in the workplace on Long Island. WOJ was a project of Resources for Program Development, Inc. (RPD), which had been established with funding from the North Shore Unitarian Universalist Society VEATCH Program. The WOJ program was initiated in October 1981 by co-founders Lillian McCormick and Charlotte Shapiro. Its mission was to foster equal employment opportunities for women and combat workplace discrimination against women in Long Island communities.
  Women in the labor movement |z United States.; Women labor union members |z United States.; Working class women--United States.
- Workers Stand for America Archived Website, Aug 25, 2012-Aug 25, 2013; Workers Stand for America
  Worker’s Stand for America is the website of a national worker’s rally that took place August 11, 2012 in Philadelphia. The rally worked to change the political focus toward job creation, worker’s rights, and education reform. The website contains a video of the entire rally, news and press releases, and their Second Bill of Rights, which is a petition that calls for the right to full employment and a living wage; the right to full participation in the electoral process; right to a voice at work, the right to quality education; and the right to a secure, healthy future.
- WORKING AMERICA Archived Website, Oct 23, 2011 - ongoing; Working America
  Working America, founded in 2003, is an allied organization of the AFL-CIO which works to build alliances among non-union working people. Working America is a nonpartisan, non-profit organization which provides workers who are not union members input into the policies, goals, and legislative efforts of the AFL-CIO. It also recruits people to help with letter-writing campaigns, canvassing, and other activities to promote causes important to the labor federation.
  Labor movement |z United States.; Labor unions |z United States.
- Working-Class Perspectives Archived Website, Jan 19, 2010-ongoing; Center for Working-Class Studies at Youngstown State University (Ohio).
  Working-Class Perspectives (founded July, 2008) is the blog of the Center for Working-Class Studies at Youngstown State University (Ohio). Working-Class Perspectives offers weekly commentaries on current issues related to working-class people and communities. Contributors discuss a variety of issues, from what class means to how it intersects with race and gender to how class is shaping American politics.
  Labor movement |z United States.; Labor unions |z United States.; Working class |z United States.
- WorkingLife Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Labor Research Association (U.S.).
  WorkingLife.org is the blog of the Labor Research Association (LRA), which was founded in 1927 to collect data on labor for trade unions and publish that information, statistics, and related news, and was for many years informally associated with the Communist Party USA. The Labor Research Association is a New York City-based non-profit research and advocacy organization that provides research and educational services for trade unions. LRA's work is overseen by a Board of Directors composed of union leaders and others involved in the labor movement. The website fosters discussion on work, the economy, and labor.
  Industrial relations |z United States.; Labor economics |z United States.; Labor movement |x Political activity |z United States.
- Writers Guild of America, East Inc. (WGAE) Archived Website, Dec 9, 2009 - ongoing; Writers Guild of America, East.
  The Writers Guild of America, East, founded in 1951, is a labor union of thousands of professionals who are the primary creators of what is seen or heard on television and film in the U.S., as well as digital media content. The Guild negotiates contracts, make sure on-screen credits are fair and accurate, and provides education and training for members. The Writers Guild of America, East is affiliated with the Writers Guild of America, West. Together the guilds administer the Writers Guild of America Awards. It is an affiliate of both the International Federation of Journalists and the International Affiliation of Writers Guilds, as well as an affiliate of the AFL-CIO.